Now I want to talk a little bit more about eye contact and I'm going to give you a tip for making eye contact with the entire audience.
Sometimes it can be a little overwhelming to look at everyone in the audience.
You might think of doing it this way.
You might think of creating a pattern, meaning, I'm going to look at that group, then that group, then that group, then this group, then center.
Or, maybe you make a Z formation.
Maybe you look right, center, left, center, right, something.
But create a pattern so that one, you don't get stuck somewhere and two, it's more of a mechanical thing in the sense of all the groups are the same.
This is group A, this is group B, this is group C. I'm going to make sure to cover A, B, C, C, B, A.
However it is, come up with a pattern.
And the reason why this is so important is because by looking at the entire audience, you'll be able to see how they are responding to you as a speaker.
They will be giving you visual feed back so that you can adjust something if you need to.
Maybe you need to, you know if people are looking like they don't know what you're talking about, perhaps you need to slow down.
Whatever it is, it can give you cues and clues to how you?re doing as you're giving your speech.